tsbvi.edu 2010-06-15

# About the TSBVI Web Site

This page and the entire TSBVI World Wide Web site strives to be accessible to all people.

### Purpose

The Texas School for the Blind and Visually Impaired World Wide Web site reflects the schools vision of serving as a leading center of educational expertise for students with visual impairments. The TSBVI website strives to be a model for web site design to ensure the information is accessible to individuals with visual impairments. Such information can be easily transformed into Braille, large print, voice output, and regular text. As a technical information resource, the site will focus on four areas:

> **Training** \- materials to support training and education, announcements of upcoming training events, and provision of on-line training

> **Research** \- provide for the ongoing development and dissemination of research information developed here at TSBVI, within the State of Texas, and elsewhere. It is our hope that such information will coordinate the efforts of professionals working in the classroom, educational center, and academic context

> **Curricula** \- provide for the efficient sharing of information concerning education of students with visual impairments.

> **Technical** \- provide resources for professionals, parents, and lay persons associated with programs for the visually impaired and deaf/blind throughout the state, country, and world

All resources on the TSBVI Web page are in the public domain unless otherwise noted. You are welcome to use these resources as needed provided that the TSBVI Web page is cited as the source. A basic tenet of TSBVI is to promote the collegial sharing of information. You are invited to submit items for publication on the website. In all cases author contact information will be included. In this manner, we hope to build a valuable resource to promote the development of instructional materials and resources.

## Disclaimer of Endorsement

All articles appearing on this website represent the individual positions of their authors and not the position of the Texas School for the Blind and Visually Impaired.

The TSBVI website contains a variety of links and references to resources available through government, educational, commercial, nonprofit, and international websites. External links to websites from the TSBVI website and references to non-TSBVI resources are provided solely for informational purposes and the convenience of the user. The Texas School for the Blind and Visually Impaired does not control, review, approve, or endorse these sites or the information, products or services contained therein. These other sites may collect data or personal information. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of the new site. If you decide to access any site linked to this site, you do so entirely at your own risk. In addition, the external links and resources are in no way intended to represent an exhaustive listing.

### Accessibility Policy

The Texas School for the Blind and Visually Impaired (TSBVI) is committed to making its Web site accessible to all users. To make the site more accessible, we include several features designed to improve accessibility for users with disabilities. Some of these features are described below.

A descriptive text equivalent is provided for images and other non-text elements, aiding users who listen to the content of the site by using a screen reader, rather than reading the site.

Major reports and other publications that are on the Web site are generally available in HTML or other accessible format. When publishing a document in Adobe Portable Document Format (PDF), we will also post an accessible version.

TSBVI is committed to making its Web site accessible according to the standards set forth by the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) [Web Content Accessibility Guidelines](http://www.w3.org/TR/WAI-WEBCONTENT) and the [Section 508 Web Accessibility Standards.](http://www.section508.gov/index.cfm?FuseAction=Content&ID=12#Web) To improve the accessibility of our Web site, we test any major redesign with screen readers and other tools. The results of these reviews are incorporated into the Web site.

TSBVI welcomes comments on how to improve the site's accessibility for users with disabilities. If you use assistive technology and the format of any material on our Web site interferes with your ability to access the information, please [contact the webmaster](mailto:jimallan@tsbvi.edu). To enable us to respond in a manner most helpful to you, please indicate the nature of your accessibility problem, the preferred format in which to receive the material, the Web address of the requested material, and your contact information. 

Additional information about accessibility programs in Texas is available from the [Governor's Committee on People with Disabilities](http://www.governor.state.tx.us/disabilities).

If you have a visual impairment there are many options which you can control from the selection of an accessible browser to modifying your browser to meet your needs. Visit Large Print and Speech Access to the World Wide Web.

Questons about accessibility?

* * *

### Privacy Policy

The Texas School for the Blind and Visually Impaired maintains this web site as a public service. The following is the privacy policy for this site (all pages starting with www.tsbvi.edu):

  1. We do not use cookies to collect information. Note: A cookie file contains unique information a web site can use to track such things as passwords, lists of pages you've visited, and the date when you last looked at a specific page or to identify your session at a particular web site. A cookie is often used in commercial sites to identify the items selected for a specific shopping cart application.
  2. If you send us an electronic mail message with a question or comment that contains personally identifying information, or fill out a form that e-mails us this information, we will only use the personally-identifiable information to respond to your request and analyze trends. We may redirect your message to another government agency or person who is in a better position to answer your question.
  3. For site management functions, information is collected for analysis and statistical purposes. This information is not reported or used in any manner that would reveal personally identifiable information, and will not be released to any outside parties unless legally required to do so in connection with law enforcement investigations or other legal proceedings.

We use Log analysis tools to create summary statistics, which are used for purposes such as assessing what information is of most interest, determining technical design specifications, and identifying system performance or problem areas. The following information is collected for this analysis:

  * **User Client hostname** \- The hostname (or IP address if DNS is disabled) of the user/client requesting access.
  * **HTTP header, "user-agent"** \- The user-agent information includes the type of browser, its version, and the operating system it's running on.
  * **HTTP header, "referer"** \- The referer specifies the page from which the client accessed the current page.
  * **System date** \- The date and time of the user/client request.
  * **Full request** \- The exact request the user/client made.
  * **Status** \- The status code the server returned to the user/client.
  * **Content length** \- The content length, in bytes, of the document sent to the user/client.
  * **Method** \- The request method used.
  * **Universal Resource Identifier (URI)** \- The location of a resource on the server.
  * **Query string of the URI** \- Anything after the question mark in a URI.
  * **Protocol** \- The transport protocol and version used.

* * *

### Submission Guidelines

  * Use a FAQ structure (see bnsemail.htm as an example)
  * Identify sources of quoted materials (link to source when available)
  * When referencing specific products provide a link to appropriate manufacturer's product page
  * Provide complete author information. Name, Organization, Address, E-mail.
  * Submit publications for consideration to [Jim Allan](mailto:allanj@tsbvi.edu)

* * *

### Open Records Policy

* * *

Agency Contact Information | [Texas State Homepage](http://www.state.tx.us/) | [Texas State Wide Search](http://www.tsl.state.tx.us/trail/)

Please complete the comment form or send comments and suggestions to: Jim Allan ([Webmaster-Jim Allan](mailto:jimallan@tsbvi.edu))

Last Revision: August 26, 2009
